Guide to the Engin Ozendes Collection of Ottoman photography AD.MC.012
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
- Portrait of a man in a wool collared shirt with dark hair parted on his right, looking off to the left. 28 x 21.7 cm, 7 May 1918 (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Constantinople; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Studio Photography; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits
- Mosque portal from the Nuruosmaniye Mosque with muqarnas and plaque. 26.9 x 20.9 cm, 1900 (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Men; Mosques; Nuruosmaniye Mosque; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Doors/Entrances; Arabic Calligraphy; Religious Sites; Architecture
- Studio portrait of Fazil and Fazilet. 28 x 18.9 cm, 27 September 1928 (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Books; Painted Backdrops; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Girls; Boys; Istanbul, Turkey; Group Portraits; Ottoman Writing
- Man with a mustache, wearing a fez and a high-collared shirt with a dark tie, looking off to the left. 24.9 x 16.6 cm, Undated (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Fez/Tarboush; Individual Portraits; Istanbul, Turkey; Facial Hair; Facial Hair; Constantinople; Photographic Prints; Ottoman Writing; Hats
- Group photo with numerous men in light-colored military uniforms, some standing and some sitting in the yard of a building among some foliage. 18.4 x 25.7 cm, Undated (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Flags; Hand Fans; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Turkey; Weapons; Men; Women; Hats; Group Portraits; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Canes/Walking Sticks; Swords/Knives; Facial Hair
- Man with beard holding a long-handled whip, wearing high leather boots with spurs, a brimmed hat and a wide printed cummerbund around his waist. His right foot is set on a pedestal and his right hand on a tilted column. 22.6 x 21.6 cm, Undated; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Individual Portraits; Constantinople; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Albumen Prints; Facial Hair; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Furnishings; Hats; Men
- Tree of the Janissaries in the courtyard of the Topkapi Palace (189. L'Arbre de la Jannissaires). 25.6 x 20.5 cm, Circa 1894 (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Istanbul, Turkey; Buildings; Animals; Men; Topkapi Palace; Outdoors; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Sheep; Outdoors; Palaces; French Writing; Fez/Tarboush; Facial Hair; Hats
- Toddler girl in a light-colored lace-trimmed dress, sitting on an upholstered curule seat. Turkish writing on back: "Gift from the Armenian Patriarchate of Istanbul." 27.5 x 17.3 cm, Undated (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Albumen Prints; Constantinople; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Painted Backdrops; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Individual Portraits; Furnishings; Children; Girls; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Turkish Writing
- Ottoman Pasha and the head guard of Wilhelm II in Baalbek. 23.6 x 30.2 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Military/Soldiers; Albumen Prints; Baalbek, Lebanon; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Men; Pasha; Weapons; Hats; Fez/Tarboush; Swords/Knives; Uniforms; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Medals/Insignia; Wilhelm II, German Emperor, 1859-1941
- Panoramic view of Istanbul overlooking the Golden Horn. 20.5 x 26.1 cm, 1894 (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Bosphorus; Istanbul, Turkey; Bridges; The Golden Horn/Haliç; Albumen Prints; Rivers; Boats/Ships; Boats/Ships; Buildings; Landscapes
- Entrance to Yedikule Fortress with four men standing in front with a boy seated on the bridge. 19.9 x 25.1 cm., 1860 (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Landscapes; Children; Turkey; Boys; Street Vendors; Men; Forts/Castles; Istanbul, Turkey; Food; Food; Albumen Prints
- Tomb of Sultan Selim II with man seated on left hand side of the door and tiled art on either side. 21 x 26.9 cm., 1895 (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Tombs/Mausoleums; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Architecture; Mosques; Albumen Prints; Ottoman Writing; Arabic Calligraphy; Doors/Entrances; Religious Sites; Individual Portraits
- Nuruosmaniye Mosque Gate with street vendors. 20.9 x 26.7 cm., Circa 1890 (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Arabic Calligraphy; Street Vendors; Men; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Mosques; Nuruosmaniye Mosque; Architecture; Doors/Entrances; Religious Sites; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Fez/Tarboush; Hats
- Interior of Bayezid I Mosque (Yildirim Sultan Bayazid) with four men kneeling and chandaliers hanging low. 26.6 x 20.7 cm, 1894 (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Mosques; Gelatin Silver Prints; Religious Ceremony; Men; Architecture; Photographic Prints; Bursa, Turkey; Religious Sites; Group Portraits; Praying; Arabic Calligraphy; Lanterns/Lamps; French Writing
- The tree of the Janissaries with 3 men to the left, one man hidden in the hollow, and one man to the right of the tree. 21.8 x 26.8 cm, 1889 (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Outdoors; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Topkapi Palace; Constantinople; Men; Outdoors; Istanbul, Turkey; Palaces; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Smoking; French Writing
- Bayezid II Mosque exterior with pigeons in the courtyard. 21.2 x 26.8 cm., 1890 (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Outdoors; Street Vendors; Men; Mosques; Birds; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Animals; Albumen Prints; Architecture; Religious Sites; French Writing
- Ablution fountain outside the Bayezid II Mosque. 21.6 x 26.6 cm., 1894 (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Mosques; Bayezid II Mosque; Men; Architecture; Fountains; Animals; Birds; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Religious Sites; Fountains; French Writing
- Suleymaniye Mosque exterior. 20.8 x 26.9 cm., 1900 (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Suleymaniye Mosque; Mosques; Religious Sites; Men; Architecture; Outdoors; Istanbul, Turkey; French Writing
- Side view of Cifte Minareli Medrese with four people standing by the gate and one man standing to the left and a person carrying stacks of cloth across the street. 23.9 x 17.5 cm., Undated (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Turkish Writing; Erzurum, Turkey; Schools/Education; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Architecture; Buildings
- Train and bridge on the Istanbul-Ankara railway, opened in 1892. With General Omer Fahreddin (Pasha) Turkkan. 19 x 25.5 cm., Undated (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Turkey; Bridges; Men; Trains; Photographic Prints; Pasha; Albumen Prints; Railways; Transportation; Turkish Writing; Türkkan, Ömer Fahrettin (Fakhri Pasha), 1868-1948
- Military Academy cadets standing before a bridge on the Istanbul-Ankara railway, opened in 1892. With General Omer Fahreddin (Pasha) Turkkan. 25.8 x 19 cm., 1891 (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Bridges; Turkey; Railways; Weapons; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Men; Military/Soldiers; Trains; Swords/Knives; Uniforms; Pasha; Group Portraits; Transportation; Facial Hair; Canes/Walking Sticks; Fez/Tarboush; Türkkan, Ömer Fahrettin (Fakhri Pasha), 1868-1948
- Ottoman military academy students and rail workers standing in front of a train tunnel on the Istanbul-Ankara railway, opened in 1892. With General Omer Fahreddin (Pasha) Turkkan. 19 x 25.4 cm., Undated (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Military/Soldiers; Turkey; Trains; Uniforms; Railways; Pasha; Men; Tunnels; Group Portraits; Transportation; Facial Hair; Hats; Canes/Walking Sticks; Fez/Tarboush; Türkkan, Ömer Fahrettin (Fakhri Pasha), 1868-1948
- Ottoman military academy students and railway workers standing in front of a tunnel on the Istanbul - Ankara Railway. Turkish writing on attached paper. 14.3 x 14 cm, 1891; Türkkan, Ömer Fahrettin (Fakhri Pasha), 1868-1948 (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Men; Hats; Fez/Tarboush; Turkish Writing; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Trains; Turkey; Railways; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Tunnels; Group Portraits; Transportation; Facial Hair; Hats
- Major General Giritli Ismail of the Ottoman cavalry. 16.8 x 23 cm, Circa 1890 (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Horses; Individual Portraits; Animals; Turkey; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Men; Fez/Tarboush; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Facial Hair; Hats
- Kaiser Wilhelm II during his visit to Umayyad Mosque in Damascus. 23.5 x 32.5 cm, 1898 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Flags; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Hats; Architecture; Mosques; Damascus, Syria; Men; Religious Sites; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Medals/Insignia; Wilhelm II, German Emperor, 1859-1941
- Actors on a stage performing a production based on the battle of Sakarya. 11.5 x 17.8 cm, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Arabic Writing; Turkey; Turkish Writing; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Costumes; Performance Plays; Theater; Wars; Group Portraits; Men; Women; Facial Hair
- The interior courtyard of the Manisa Sultan Mosque. 17 x 12.1 cm, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Religious Sites; Men; Mosques; Manisa, Turkey; Manisa Sultan Mosque; Turkish Writing; Architecture; Facial Hair; Fez/Tarboush; Hats
- Two three-masted ships in a body of water with mountains in the background. 11.9 x 16.2 cm, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Seas; Boats/Ships; Photographic Prints; Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mountains/Hills; Landscapes
- Men wearing bowler and cylinder hats, men in regional dress and saddled camels. 11.4 x 15.4 cm, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Facial Hair; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Hats; Men; Camels; Regional/National Dress; Animals; Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Albumen Prints; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Outdoors; Buildings; Lanterns/Lamps
- Group of seven men standing and sitting in front of the Porch of the Caryatids at the Erechtheion Temple on the north side of the Acropolis in Athens, Greece. 12 x 16.5 cm, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Photographic Prints; Hats; Men; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Albumen Prints; Athens, Greece; Acropolis of Athens; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
- Group of masted ships in dock, one with the name "Helios" another in the distance with a two-word name, the second of which is "Teresa" 11.9 x 16.2 cm, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Flags; Docks/Piers/Jetties; Boats/Ships; Turkey; Photographic Prints
- Man, sitting next to a sheep, smoking a pipe and a boy sitting on the curb of a street. Covered wheeled carts sit behind a fence with covers on them labeled "RUSTON PROCTOR LINCOLN ENGLAND" 12 x 16.5 cm, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Photographic Prints; Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair; Streets/Roads; Facial Hair; Animals; Children; Men; Boys; Sheep; Advertisements; Carriages/Coaches; Smoking; Turbans; Group Portraits; Tobacco pipes; Agriculture/Farms
- Fisherman standing on a boat, pulling in a net in the foreground, three two-masted ships in the background. 12 x 16.5 cm, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Mountains/Hills; Boats/Ships; Fishing; Individual Portraits; Turkey; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Water; Boats/Ships; Men
- Two men, one in a bowler hat, talking on the street in front of a street produce market. Piles of melons are stached against the wall of a building. 12 x 16.5 cm, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Turkey; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Men; Streets/Roads; Street Vendors; Group Portraits; Food; Streets/Roads
- Five men praying on a prayer rug on the deck of a ship, one man looks directly at the camera. A lifeboat hanging in the background indicates the boat is from Liverpool. 12 x 16.5 cm, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Boats/Ships; Men; Praying; Sailors; Hats; Regional/National Dress; Turbans; Turkey; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
- The Tsar Cannon on display on the grounds of the Moscow Kremlin in Russia. A small boy sits on the pedestal on which the cannon is placed. 12 x 16.5 cm, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Kremlin (Moscow), Russia; Military/Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Moscow, Russia; Cannons; Men; Weapons
- A man in a hat and apron sitting hunched over, working on a street. Two men sit to the left, one smoking, and another man stands to the right. 12 x 16.4 cm, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Street Vendors; Streets/Roads; Men; Turkey; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Smoking; Group Portraits
- Man in a hat walking across a street with a cane under his left arm. In the background, men load melons onto baskets slung over a donkey's back. 12 x 16.4 cm, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Turkey; Streets/Roads; Canes/Walking Sticks; Men; Animals; Individual Portraits; Donkeys; Buildings; Street Lamps; Food
- Tsar Bell, Moscow, Russia. A man in a uniform stands in the foreground. 16.4 x 12 cm, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Moscow, Russia; Kremlin (Moscow), Russia; Individual Portraits; Uniforms; Men; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Military/Soldiers
- Portrait of a standing man with mustache and goatee wearing a high light-colored collar and a three-piece. 16.4 x 12 cm, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Facial Hair; Facial Hair; Men; Individual Portraits
- Mausoleum of Saladin, Damascus. 27.1 x 20.7 cm, Undated; Bonfils, Felix (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Mausoleum of Saladin; Damascus, Syria; Tombs/Mausoleums; Buildings; Architecture; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Religious Sites; French Writing
- Ras Beirut seen from a cliff on the side of a harbor. 20.5 x 26.9 cm, Circa 1870; Bonfils, Felix (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Water; Lebanon; Buildings; Fishing; Boats/Ships; Beirut, Lebanon; Landscapes
- Guards and other men standing in front of Beiteddine Palace, Lebanon. 20.5 x 27 cm, Circa 1880; Bonfils, Felix (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Fountains; Gelatin Silver Prints; Uniforms; Photographic Prints; Buildings; Men; Architecture; Palaces; Beit ed-Dine, Lebanon; Street Lamps
- Temple of the Sun (also called the Temple of Jupiter) in Baalbek, Lebanon. 20.5 x 27 cm, Circa 1880; Bonfils, Felix (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Temples; Baalbek, Lebanon; Religious Sites; Landscapes
- Port of Mersin, Turkey (Port de Mersina, Syria). 20.5 x 27 cm, Circa 1870; Bonfils, Felix (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Boats/Ships; Mersin, Turkey; Ports; Photographic Prints; Boats/Ships; Gelatin Silver Prints; Docks/Piers/Jetties; Buildings; Water; Landscapes; French Writing
- Building interior with furnishings. In the foreground stands a couch, round table and four upholstered spindle-back chairs. 35 x 27.8 cm, Undated; Bonfils, Felix (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Unknown Locations; Architecture; Furnishings; Lanterns/Lamps
- Columns of the Temple of the Sun (also called the Temple of Jupiter) and surrounding ruins in Baalbek, Lebanon. 27.8 x 35.1 cm, Undated; Bonfils, Felix (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Temples; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Photographic Prints; Baalbek, Lebanon; Albumen Prints; Religious Sites; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
- Man with a mustache standing with his right arm on a column in a long, dark jacket, light vest and shirt, a dark bow tie and a ring on his right little finger. 10.5 x 6.2 cm, Undated; Bonfils, Felix (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Jewelry; Bow Ties; Carpets/Rugs; Facial Hair; Men; Syria; Beirut, Lebanon; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair; Albumen Prints
- Woman wearing a light colored lace-trimmed top. 41.4 x 34.3 cm, 25 [...?] 1916 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Individual Portraits; Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women; Greek Writing
- Woman with a crescent shaped hair ornament. 43 x 35 cm, 1910 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Women; Jewelry; Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Albumen Prints
- Tomb of Sultan Murad II in the Muradiye Complex, Bursa, Turkey. The tomb sits on a stone pedestal and exposed soil can be seen on the surface of the tomb. 31.6 x 35.5 cm, Undated; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Bursa, Turkey; Religious Sites; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Tombs/Mausoleums; Muradiye Complex; French Writing
- Gate of the Sultan at Dolmabahce Palace, Istanbul (Porte du Palais de Dolma-Bachteh). 31.8 x 36.8 cm, Undated; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Architecture; Dolmabahce Palace; Palaces; Buildings; French Writing
- The Great Mabeyn Pavilion at Yildiz Palace, Istanbul, Turkey (832). 31.7 x 34.4 cm, Undated; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Architecture; Yildiz Palace; Palaces; Buildings; Street Lamps
- Fountain on a street with the Aziziye Mosque in the background. 31.8 x 36.4 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Albumen Prints; Mosques; Outdoors; Street Vendors; Fountains; Men; Horses; Architecture; Konya, Turkey; Aziziye Mosque; Animals; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites
- Sultan Ahmed Mosque (The Blue Mosque) Istanbul, Turkey. 32 x 42.6 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Religious Sites; Outdoors; Blue Mosque/Sultan Ahmed Mosque; Mosques; Architecture; Istanbul, Turkey; Buildings
- Ablution fountain in the courtyard of Selimiye Mosque in Edirne, Turkey. A group of men gather around the fountain, looking toward the camera. French writing on front. 29.9 x 43 cm, 1894 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  French Writing; Religious Sites; Men; Architecture; Fountains; Mosques; Selimiye Mosque; Photographic Prints; Edirne, Turkey; Albumen Prints
- Dolmabahce Mosque with ships sailing in the Bosphorus in the background. 32.1 x 43.3 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Boats/Ships; Architecture; Istanbul, Turkey; Bosphorus; Dolmabahce Mosque; Mosques; Religious Sites; Buildings; Landscapes; French Writing
- Family portrait. 32.8 x 40 cm, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Constantinople; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Facial Hair; Studio Photography; Facial Hair; Furnishings; Girls; Women; Men; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Group Portraits; Children; French Writing
- Ramla, the Tower of the 40 Martyrs (White Mosque). 20.3 x 25.7 cm, 1865 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Ramla/ar-Ramlah; White Mosque, Ramla; Architecture; Men; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Churches; Religious Sites; Palestine; Mosques
- Panorama of the city of Ramla with a graveyard in the foreground. 20.6 x 26.9 cm, Circa 1870 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Outdoors; Buildings; Landscapes; Cemeteries; Tombs/Mausoleums; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Ramla/ar-Ramlah; Religious Sites; French Writing
- Pine forest, Beirut. 20.3 x 26.9 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Men; Children; Camels; Streets/Roads; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Beirut, Lebanon; Animals; Outdoors; Parks; French Writing
- "Portrait of two Mahometan Women," one standing, one sitting with a drum, dressed as an odalisque and servant. 26.9 x 20.4 cm, Circa 1893 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Beirut, Lebanon; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Regional/National Dress; Jewelry; Albumen Prints; Musical Instruments; Painted Backdrops; Carpets/Rugs; Furnishings; Women; Group Portraits
- Woman wearing a light veil. 35.1 x 27.8 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Women; Individual Portraits; Jewelry; Head Covers/Veils; Turkey; Studio Photography
- Two women in national dress, one standing holding a tambourine, one holding the hose of a shisha pipe. 35 x 27.8 cm, Circa 1870 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Musical Instruments; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles; Regional/National Dress; Women; Smoking; Painted Backdrops; Carpets/Rugs; Furnishings; Head Covers/Veils; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Group Portraits
- Two tents in the Forest of the Cedars of God in the Kadisha Valley in Lebanon. 27.8 x 35 cm, Circa 1870 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Forest of the Cedars of God, Ariz, Lebanon; Kadisha Valley, Lebanon; Lebanon; Outdoors; Tents; Forest/Woodlands
- Still-life of a cedar branch and cones with some stones at the bottom. Taken on Mount Lebanon (Mont Liban les Gedres). 35 x 27.8 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Lebanon; Forest of the Cedars of God, Ariz, Lebanon; Outdoors; Mount Lebanon/Jabal lubnān, Lebanon; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; French Writing
- Tekkiye Mosque (Sultan Selim Mosque) on the banks of the Barada River in Damascus. 27.8 x 35 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Albumen Prints; Damascus, Syria; Barada River; Rivers; Religious Sites; Tekkiye Mosque; Mosques; Architecture; Photographic Prints; Landscapes
- First Lieutenant Mahmud Nedim with dozens of soldiers standing on a battlefield in military uniforms and fezes. 26.8 x 33 cm, 24 August 1907 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Men; Military/Soldiers; Ottoman Writing; Turkey; Turkish Writing; Wars; Weapons; Swords/Knives; Fez/Tarboush; Outdoors; Guns; Cannons; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Hats
- First Lieutenant Mahmud Nedim. 26.8 x 33 cm, 24 August 1907 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Military/Soldiers; Turkish Writing; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Men; Wars; Guns; Cannons; Fez/Tarboush; Outdoors; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Turkey; Swords/Knives; Military/Soldiers; Weapons; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Ottoman Writing; Hats
- Group photo of soldiers with mustaches, some with beards, wearing military uniforms and fezes. 27 x 32.3 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Facial Hair; Facial Hair; Carpets/Rugs; Facial Hair; Weapons; Fez/Tarboush; Swords/Knives; Baghdad, Iraq; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Men; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Military/Soldiers; Group Portraits; Hats
- Group photo of uniformed soldiers with mustaches wearing fezes, many of whom are holding swords. In the background, a line of men stand on a terrace overhead. 26.7 x 32.5 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Baghdad, Iraq; Men; Weapons; Facial Hair; Albumen Prints; Facial Hair; Military/Soldiers; Swords/Knives; Military/Soldiers; Fez/Tarboush; Group Portraits; Hats
- Entrance to Yedikule Fortress, with a man in dark clothing and a fez standing in the foreground on an approaching road (Entrée des Sept Tours). 27.1 x 33.1 cm, Undated; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Buildings; Outdoors; Men; Forts/Castles; Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Architecture; French Writing
- Selimiye Mosque on the left and the Old Mosque of Edirne on the right. In the middle ground, carts with barrels and people are pulled by oxen and in the foreground, a boy sits smiling, looking at the camera. 23.6 x 30.2 cm, 1890; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Children; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Buildings; Boys; Men; Animals; French Writing; Old Mosque, Edirne; Mosques; Edirne, Turkey; Selimiye Mosque; Architecture; Cattle/Cows; Carriages/Coaches; Buildings; Architecture; Religious Sites; Landscapes